# RYUJI KANEKO

## Python Developer | Full Stack Web Developer

Address: Kobe, Japan



#### **SUMMARY**

As a software developer with 7 years of experience, have been collaborating with a variety of companies including small startups and big communities, which has made me intimately familiar with all the stages of the web lifecy- cle from the initial architecture to final deployment.

Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises

I am competent across the full stack web development, and I am not new to remote work, so my working hours are very flexible.

Also, Over the past two years, I have accumulated a lot of knowledge about data engineering by working on several projects based on data science, such as data integration and data analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Science**

**Kobe University** 

GPA 3.8 / 4.0

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Python Developer

## KAIZEN PLATFORM

**=** 08/2022 - 07/2023

- Made over 600 insertions and 100 deletions to 4 central Firmware repositories in less than 3 months
- Participated in more than 3 projects from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases
- Developed data quality portal using Python scripting, increasing data quality by 30%
- Communicated and coordinated with the project manager and coworkers to resolve 30+ build breaks a month

## Data Engineer

## Argosgrafix

**=** 09/2021 - 07/2022

- Streamlined the software's codebase, improving performance and maintainability.
- Visualised over 40 datasets with Matplotlib
- Utilized Python libraries, like NumPy and Pandas, for complex data analysis and modeling
- Delivering projects with 1-2 days turn around time or even within hours

## Frontend Developer

#### THE LLOYD GROUP INC.

**=** 06/2020 - 08/2021

Hottolink is a Technology company that specializes in Big Data and analytics solutions.

- Redesigned and rebuilt 3 websites, driving remarkable growth for over 2
- Converted 2 traditional web apps to single-page apps with AJAX and state management techniques in JavaScript.
- Created 4 compelling and interactive charts and animations using Recharts, Highcharts, CSS, and JavaScript.
- roubleshot and resolved over 20 front-end rendering performance issues and computationally intensive bot-tlenecks using Chrome DevTools.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Languages

JavaScrip	t Ty	peScript	ECI	ECMAScript	
HTML5/C	SS 3	SCSS/SA	ASS	GraphQL	
Python	Ruby	C++			

## Frameworks & Libraries

jQuery	React	React Native	<u> </u>	
Three.js	D3.js	Angular	Next	
Vue E	Vue BootStrap		SS	
Node.js	Nest.js	Django	Flask	
Ruby on Rails Data Engineering				
Data Analysis & Visualization				
Unit Testi	ng			

#### Database/Storage/Platforms

MongoDB	MySQL	PostgreSQ	L —
Firebase	Google Clo	ud Storage	AWS
GCP			

## **Tools**

Git	Gitl	Hub	Gi	tLab	Bitbucket
Jira	Postman			REST Console	
Swag	ger	Slac	k_	Doc	ker
WebP	ack				

CV Enhancy

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Front-end Engineer

#### CORETELLIGENT

**=** 05/2018 - 04/2020

- Collaborated with a client and 4 cross-functional teams to plan, develop, test, and deploy high-quality software solutions.
- Designed an application architecture that became the company standard for optimal performance and scala- bility using React, TypeScript, Jest.
- Directed over 10 features and user interfaces to optimize performance of user-facing products, and mentored 2 front-end developers for maintainable and high-quality code.
- Led code reviews for 2 front-end developers to ensure code quality and maintainability.
- Optimized Webpack build process for an 80% reduction in build times and bundle sizes, resulting in faster de-ployment and 75% improved performance.
- Constructed 2 admin and client dashboards with complex data visualization and user-friendly search features using React.
- Conducted technical workshops for 5 colleagues on topics such as Regular Expressions and Redux.
- Advised as a trusted technology advisor to 2 designers, ensuring alignment with business goals and objectives.

## Software Development Engineer - Intern

#### Amazon

**=** 02/2018 - 05/2018

- Streamlined 1 website using JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, and commercial/open-source tools from wireframes and visual designs.
- Translated Figma designs into responsive web pages with animations using HTML5/CSS3 and web-based ani- mation tools.
- Conducted extensive testing across multiple browsers and devices to ensure optimal performance and com- patibility.
- Utilized rapid prototyping techniques to quickly test and refine new ideas, improving concept quality.

## Freelance Full-stack developer

## Freelancer

**=** 10/2015 - 12/2017

- Developed 2 MERN and MEAN stack applications using agile methodologies.
- Built 5 custom websites with HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, and Laravel/PHP API endpoints.
- Created 1 front-end widget as a single external script using vanilla JavaScript.
- Managed the entire product development lifecycle and solved 2 payment integration challenges with high pre- cision for various user banks.
- Proficient with various web development tools, including Git and Cloud Services such as AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku, and Netlify.

#### STRENGTHS

## Time management

Prioritizes essential tasks so they are not rushed. Sets deadlines that ensure reaching milestones on time.

## 00

0

## Adaptability

I remember that change is not personal and is inevitable. I break my projects into multiple parts so that if something goes wrong, I can quickly fix it.



## Accountability

I take ownership of my mistakes. By doing that I learn what I did wrong so that it does not happen again.

